(日向翔陽)すぅふぅ
The last set.
≪ファイナルセト≫
(池尻･
((勝てよたくさん勝てよ
Win!
You have to keep winning!
≪これを落とせば
If we drop the ball now...
終わり≫
it's over.
Episode Twenty-three:
The Play to Shift the Momentum
Nice receive!
(田中)ナイスレシブ
(金田一)≪１０番≫
Number ten!
(岩泉)((たぶんもう神業速攻の
サインは変えてきてるよな))
They've probably changed their signal
for the superhuman fast attack by now.
(及川)
((単純なサインだからきと
It's a simple signal, so they can swap it as much as they want.
いくらでも替えが利くんだよね))
(金田一)((それでも
何か見分けるヒントは
There still has to be some kind of tell-tale hint.
(松川)((ボルを
目で長く追てるようなら
If he's been tracking the ball, it's a normal fast attack.
普通の速攻
ただ突込んでくるときは神業
And if he dives right in, it's superhuman?
(花巻)((確かに
１０番自体を見るのがいいか))
You're right, we should be watching number ten himself.
Yes, sir.
(金田一)((はい))
(入畑)((１０番は
Number ten...
For all his talent, the small fry is just a decoy.
(及川)((でも
あくまでチビちゃんは優秀な囮))
Keep that in mind, okay?
((それを忘れないオケイ
Yes, sir!
(金田一)((はい
(一同)((うす
Yessir!
く
(金田一)しゃおらぁ
Yes!
(影山飛雄)
≪なかなか一発で決まらない
We can't seem to get it right the first time!
(嶋田)ラリ続くな
(滝ノ上)守備もブロクも
The rally continues.
Here's our chance!
On average, Seijou probably has better defense and blockers.
平均値では
青城のが上だろうけど
(澤村)フェイント
A diversion!
(滝ノ上)こちは飛び抜けて
リベロの守備力が高ぇからな
We have a libero with outstanding defensive skill.
All right!
(西谷)旭さん
(東峰)く
Asahi!
The setter received it!
(他校生)セタがレシブ
(他校生)トス上げられない
He can't make the set!
They won't be able to form much of an attack.
(他校生)攻撃単調になるぞ
(他校生)たぶんレフトだ
They'll probably go left!
渡ち
(渡)はい
Watacchi!
Yes, sir!
ふ
(青城一同)よしゃ
Karasuno                   Aoba Jousai
All right!
(繋心)もしかして
くらいに思てたんだが
Until now, it was only a hunch.
What?
(武田)え
(繋心)青城のリベロ
I think Seijou's libero was originally a setter.
もともと
セタだたのかもしれない
Atta boy!
(武田)どういうことですか
(渡)あざす
What do you mean?
Thanks, sir!
(繋心)リベロは
アタクラインよりも前で
If a libero goes past the attack line to deliver an
overhand set and someone spikes it, that is illegal.
オバハンドでのトスを上げて
それを誰かがスパイクすると
反則になる今あのリベロは
Their libero jumped just before the
attack line to deliver a set in midair.
ラインのギリ後ろで踏み切て
空中でトスを上げた
That makes a valid spike.
これならスパイクも問題ない
とさに
ハイレベルな攻撃ができる
They can set up advanced attacks instantly.
This is Aoba Jousai, the powerhouse!
(武田)これが強豪青葉城西
Olé!
(澤村)よしゃ
(田中)大地さんナイスレシブ
All right!
Daichi, nice receive!
Asahi!
旭さん
(花巻)く
(澤村)ボル戻るぞ
The ball's coming back!
≪押し込める
I have to push it over!
Take that!
(岩泉)おらぁ
ふ
ピ
All right!
(青城一同)よしゃ
あんなギリギリでトスを
He was barely able to make that set.
(２人)はぁはぁ
Incredible.
すげぇ
(繋心)よしちゃんと戦えてるぞ
落ち着いてけよ
Okay, we're playing well!
Stay calm!
(一同)はい
(繋心)中に切り込む攻撃は
Yes, sir!
They're starting to get used to our central attacks,
向こうも慣れてきてるようだから
できるだけ
so use the full width of the court as much as possible!
コトの横幅目いぱい使てけ
(一同)はい
Yes, sir!
(菅原)≪青城の
この攻撃の穴のなさはなんだ
How can there be no holes in Seijou's offense whatsoever?
どういう状況からでも
当然のように
They alter any scenario to formulate a vicious attack,
as if it was planned that way!
強烈な攻撃に繋いでくる≫
行くぞ
(一同)あす
Let's go!
Yessir!
We're definitely back on our feet after we briefly put Sugawara in the match.
(繋心)≪菅原が一度入てから
烏野は確実に立て直した≫
≪もう必要以上の
気負いも緊張もない
We've gotten rid of the unnecessary tension and pressure.
たぶん今どいつも
本来持ている力を出せている
I suspect that everyone on the team
is now playing at their true potential.
だからこそ
Is this the latent defect that truly sets the two teams apart?
じわじわと現れる
チムとしての地力の差なのか≫
Aoba Jousai               Karasuno
(岩泉)くそ
ピ
Shit!
Nice, Tsukishima!
(田中)ナイス月島
忘れた頃にやてくる
It's the dirty diversion that hits when they least expect it!
いやらしフェイント
(月島)呼び方
Phrasing.
I bet when they all put out 100%, the stronger team is Seijou.
(武田)きと
１００％の実力を出したとき
チムとして強いのは
青城なんでしょうでも
But isn't having that drop to 70% and rise again to 120%
それが７０％に落ちたり
はたまた
１２０％に跳ね上がたり
勝負て
そういうものじゃないですか
what a match is all about?
(武田)そして烏野には
And Karasuno has something that can increase its offensive power to 120%.
みんなの攻撃力を
１２０％にするための
The greatest decoy!
最強の囮がいます
≪すげぇすげぇ青城すげぇ≫
This is incredible! Seijou is incredible!
I want to play, I want to play. I want to play now.
≪出たい出たい早く出たい
早く出たい早く早く≫
I want to play now, now, now!
(菅原)日向
あはい
Hinata?
Yes?
(菅原)烏養さんが
さき言たこと覚えてるか
Do you remember what Mr. Ukai just said?
Attack using the full width of the court?
コト幅目いぱいの攻撃
ですか
Yes. And the attack that best utilizes it
そうそれに最適な攻撃
今回は
まだほとんど使てないはずだ
has barely been used in this match.
ピ
Yes!
しゃ
(及川)≪ああ嫌だ
I don't like this.
Aoba Jousai               Karasuno
チムはいたて安定してる
なのに
The team is keeping it together, but I can't help it.
あんなに小さくて下手ぴな彼が
コトに入てくることが
Whenever the tiny klutz walks on the court,
不安でしかたない
it makes me incredibly nervous.
ウォムアプゾンで
フラストレションをためた
He's the little beast who's been saving up all his frustration in the warmup zone.
小さな獣≫
≪最終セト烏野は
ようやくかみ合てきてる≫
Karasuno has finally come together in the last set.
One point!
Go, Shouyou!
Go, go!
≪それでもまだ
青城には一歩及ばない
But we're still one step short of Seijou.
そこを一歩踏み抜く可能性が
あるとしたら
If there's any possibility we can leave them a step behind,
きとお前らだ
烏野にあと一歩をくれ≫
it's probably up to you guys.
Put Karasuno that extra step ahead!
(岩泉)ナイスレシブ
(花巻)レフトレフト
Nice receive!
Left, left!
Two blockers!
(岩泉)ブロク２枚
(田中)影山ナイスワンタチ
Kageyama, nice job making contact!
(澤村)チャンスボル
This is our chance!
≪コトの横幅目いぱい≫
Use the full width
of the court!
≪来た
あの空間を裂くような
He's going for it! The air-splitting...
(及川)≪ワイドブロド
Wide broad jump!
Rule the Court
(２人)あ
(２人)あぁ
ピ
あぁ
Nice spike, Hinata!
(一同)ナイスキ日向
(西谷)翔陽
Shouyou!
≪いけない
Oh no.
Yes!
調子を上げたこのコンビを
Now that the duo is up and running,
I can't allow them to stay on the court for any length of time.
長々と
コトにいさせてはいけない≫
ピ
マキナイス
しゃ
Makki, nice!
Yes!
Spin it around!
≪回せ回せ
早くロテションを
Spin that rotation!
チビちゃんを
１秒でも早く後衛へ回せ≫
Put the small fry in the back row as quickly as possible!
(岩泉)この
(花巻)オライ
I've got it!
(ハルカ)
ボル落ちないなぁすごい
The ball just won't hit the floor. Wow.
Nice cover, Makki!
It's coming back!
(澤村)チャンスボル
We have a chance here!
Again?!
≪コトの横幅目いぱい≫
Use the full width of the court!
ピ
Aoba Jousai                    Karasuno
(烏野一同)よしゃ
All right!
だぁ
(ハルカ)あの小さい子すごい
That small kid is amazing.
Volleyball is a sport that involves jumping nonstop, so it's also like a fight against gravity.
(嶋田)バレはさとにかく
ジャンプ連発のスポツだから
重力との戦いでも
あると思うんだ
囮で跳びブロクで跳び
Jump to decoy.
Jump to block.
スパイクで跳ぶ
Jump to spike.
(澤村)西谷ナイスカバ
Nishinoya, nice cover!
(嶋田)更にラリが続いて
戻れ戻れもう一回もう一回
As the rally continues,
Back, go back! One more time!
the more uncomfortable it gets, making it harder to think.
(嶋田)苦しくなるにつれて
思考は鈍ていく
Left, left!
Let's stop it again!
It makes you want to slack off on
full-out blocks and decoy work so bad,
ぶちゃけブロクとか囮は
サボりたくなるし
スパイクも誰かほかのヤツ
打てくれて思たこともある
once I even wished someone else would spike for me.
As the long rally went on and on,
I thought with my oxygen-deprived brain,
(滝ノ上)
長いラリが続いたときは
酸欠になた頭で思たよ
ボルよ早く落ちろ
願わくは相手のコトに
"Would you just fall already, ball?
Preferably on the opponent's side of the court?"
持てこい
Send it my way!
≪ほんの一瞬でもｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞを緩めれば
取り返せない遅れになる≫
I can't drop my speed for a split-second, or I'll be put behind for good.
≪俺の身長でほんの少し
ジャンプの力を抜けば
With my height, if I don't jump as hard as I can, I'll be swatted down by the wall just like that!
高い壁に
一瞬でたたき落とされる≫
≪走れ走れ跳べ跳べ
Run, run!
Jump, jump!
≪ここにいたければ
Do it to stay here!
フリで打たせて
I'm not gonna let you hit it unmarked!
たまるか
≪今
コトの横幅目いぱい
Now! Use the full width of the court!
≪のあとの
Followed by...
≪中央突破だ
a breach through the center!
ぐ
(２人)パイプ貫通
The pipe made it past!
Nice spike!
(木下･山口･縁下)ナイスキ
(菅原)日向
Hinata!
Shit.
(岩泉)くそ
(松川)すまん完全につられた
I'm sorry.
I totally fell for it.
≪今がパイプの頃合いだと
頭では分かていた≫
In my head, I knew that the timing was right for a pipe.
Yet I nearly gave it to Hinata!
≪なのに
今日向に上げそうになた≫
≪トスを
持ていかれるところだた≫
He nearly took the set away from me.
Gutsy move, Hinata!
Thank you, sir!
≪最強の囮
The greatest decoy.
Aoba Jousai               Karasuno
(他校生)烏野追いついた
(他校生)同点だ
Karasuno caught up.
They're tied.
(山口)タオルやります
(清水)頼んだ
I'll hand out the towels.
Thank you!
(澤村)
サンキュはぁはぁはぁ
Thanks.
≪１２セト目より断然
ラリが続くようになてる≫
The rallies are way longer than in the first and second sets.
It's gotta be hard.
≪しんどいだろうなでも
But...
≪いいな≫
I'm jealous.
(花巻)どうする
１０番のあのブロド
What do we do about number ten's broad jump?
(入畑)あのブロド
(一同)ん
The broad jump...
捨てようか
has got to go.
Haikyuu !!
うらぁ
Aoba Jousai                    Karasuno
(澤村)田中ナイスキ
(田中)しゃ
Tanaka, nice spike!
Yes!
≪次のロテで日向は後衛≫
The next rotation puts Hinata in the back row.
おい元気ですか
げん元気です
Hey! How are you?!
I-I'm fine!
がつり稼いでから後衛下がれよ
当たり前だ
Rack up lots of points before you go back.
No duh!
Kunimi, nice receive!
(松川)国見ナイスレシブ
(及川)金田一
Kindaichi!
(東峰)１２番１２番
Number twelve, number twelve!
(澤村)西谷ナイスレシブ
≪チャンス
Nishinoya, nice receive!
Here's my chance!
(滝ノ上)お
またブロド来るかて
Is he going for another broad jump?! Wait.
What?
ノマク
(滝ノ上)ブロク諦めたのか
He's unmarked!
They stopped blocking!
All right, hit it in unmarked, Hinata!
よしゃ
フリで行たれ日向
≪うん≫
Yeah.
≪よく見える≫
I can see it perfectly!
(２人)は
(岩泉)渡ナイスレシブ
Watari, nice receive!
≪ノマクはわざと
≪この短時間で
He's deliberately unmarked!
Barely any time passed!
≪だとしたら
なんて切り替えの早さ≫
They change their strategy really fast!
あ
(３人)あ
ピ
(２人)ここでツアタク
Now a setter dump?!
≪こちの一瞬の動揺に
They've used our momentary confusion to get a setter dump on us!
畳みかけるツ
(入畑)
((あのブロド捨てようか))
That broad jump has got to go.
How do we do that, sir?
(金田一)
((す捨てるてどういう
(及川)((チビちゃんのあのﾌﾞﾛｰﾄﾞは
たぶん神業の方だ
The small fry's broad jump is probably another superhuman attack.
すごいスピドだけど
その勢いで体は流れて
It has terrific speed, but I suspect he gets caught up in the momentum,
コスを打ち分ける余裕は
ないんじゃないかな))
taking away his ability to be selective about its placement.
((うむ))
(及川)((あのブロドには
Yes.
We'll just have to dig out spikes from his broad jump instead of blocking them.
ブロクつかずに
ディグで対応しよう))
(渡)((はい))
(岩泉)((止められないブロクは
Yes, sir!
A block that doesn't work just interferes with the receive.
レシブの邪魔するだけだしな))
(入畑)((どんな苦しいときでも
お互いの意思疎通と
No matter how hard it gets, never stop thinking or understanding one another!
考えることをやめるなよ
Nice receive!
(繋心)≪あのブロドでも
崩せねぇのか青城≫
Isn't his broad jump enough to disrupt Seijou?
≪くそ相手を
いちばん乗せたくないときに
Shit.
Just when we least wanted our opponent to get into a rhythm,
こいつのサブの番が来やがる≫
it's his turn to serve.
一本で切る
(西谷)うす
Let's stop him here.
Olé!
Yessir!
What the...
ありゃ
It went over the net!
Rule the Court
(部員)ネトイン
(部員)よしゃラキ
Talk about lucky!
今のはしかたねぇ
切り替えろ
That was unavoidable!
Just stay focused!
≪くそまた２点差焦るな≫
Shit, they have another two point buffer.
Keep cool.
ピ
(青城応援団)それ
Olé!
(西谷)すまんカバ
(２人)オライ
Sorry! Cover me!
I've got it!
あ
(澤村)影山旭ラスト
Kageyama!
Asahi, last hit!
We have a chance here!
あぶね
落ち着け焦るな
That was close!
Left!
Calm down! Keep cool!
く
わあ
なかなか決まらないなぁ
Whoa, it's really hard to make it count!
長いラリを制すれば
流れをつかむキカケになる
Taking control of a long rally is one way to gain momentum.
このラリからの１点重いぞ
The point earned from this rally will be huge!
(澤村)カバ
≪点も流れも渡してたまるか
Cover it!
I'm not letting you have this point or the momentum!
(嶋田)おお繋いだ
(滝ノ上)でもラスト誰打つ
Oh, it's still in play!
But who will make the last hit?!
Center!
センタ
翔陽頼む
Shouyou, it's all yours!
(３人)ぶち抜け
Get through!
Stop him!
(３人)止めろ
く
(２人)よしゃ
All right!
Aoba Jousai               Karasuno
(滝ノ上)ああタイムアウト
２回とも使いきちまた
Now they've used up both timeouts.
(嶋田)まあしかたねぇよ
What else could they do?
タイムアウトで
物理的に流れ切らなきゃ
Unless they use a timeout to physically stop Seijou's momentum, they'll run away with the match.
マジで
このまま青城に持ていかれる
≪何か何かないか
流れを変える何か≫
Isn't there something, anything,
that can change the momentum?
≪切り札とかじゃなくていい
一本
We don't need big guns. I just want one play.
ほんの少しの空気を変える
一本が欲しい≫
Just one play to clear the air!
Seijou touched the net!
青城にタチネト
I'm sorry!
It's fine!
うへ助かた
でも
Thank goodness.
Still...
≪これで
チビちゃんは後衛に下がた≫
Now the small fry is in the back row!
It's up to you.
Yes, sir.
(嶋田)ここでミスたら
青城は２０点の大台
If we screw this up, Seijou will have twenty points!
Hinata, relax!
Yes, sir!
流れ持てかれると
追いつけなくなるぞ
And if they take the momentum
along with it, we'll never catch up!
(滝ノ上)おい嶋田あれ
Hey, Shimada. Look.
た忠がピンチサバ
T-Tadashi is their pinch server?!
繋心何考えてんだアホか
What is Keishin thinking? Is he dumb?!
まだせいぜい
まぐれ当たりだて言たろうが
I told him that he only flukes them at best!
(滝ノ上)そのまぐれ当たりでさえ
欲しいてことなんだろ
It probably means he's hoping for a fluke.
ん
(滝ノ上)流れつうのは
You never know what will change the momentum.
どからどう変わるか
分かんねぇもんなんだからな
(花巻)烏野にピンサ
(渡)サブが得意なのか
Karasuno's pinch server?
Is he good at serving?
それとも
単純に空気変えるためですかね
Or is it simply to clear the air?
(岩泉)
どちみち流れは渡さねぇよ
Either way, we aren't giving up the momentum.
山口ナイサ
Yamaguchi, you can do this.
でも負けねぇかんな
But you won't beat me!
≪一瞬でも
下げられるのが嫌なんだな≫
He hates being out of the match, even for a second.
(繋心)山口流れ変えてこい
ははい
Yamaguchi!
Go change the momentum!
Y-Yes, sir!
(山口)≪この線
This line.
この線の向こうは違う世界だ≫
A different world lies on the other side of it.
≪こち側は
気温が違うみたいだ≫
I think the temperature is different on this side.
(田中)
おう大抜擢じゃねぇか山口
Way to score a huge promotion, Yamaguchi!
(山口)はい
(澤村)一発行たれ山口
Yes, sir!
Take a shot at 'em, Yamaguchi!
ナイサ
(東峰)ナナイサ
Give us a good serve.
G-Give us a good one. T-Take it nice and easy now.
き気楽に行けよ
Asahi, do you understand what nice and easy means?!
(澤村)
旭気楽の意味分かてるのか
Yikes! Being put in the match now would freak out anyone!
≪うおこのタイミングは
誰だてビビるわ≫
≪これが高校初試合初サブとか
心臓出るコチドＳか
This is his first match and first serve in high school! It's terrifying!
Is the coach a sadist or something?!
≪こちも緊張する
いかん山口に伝わる平常心≫
It's even making me tense.
Don't! Yamaguchi will pick up on it! Composure!
≪日向が打つよりは
後頭部が安全だな≫
I think the back of my head is safer without Hinata serving.
(縁下)大丈夫ですかね
ただでさえ緊張する場面で
Is this safe?
This situation is already tense enough.
２３年差し置いて出る
プレシャもあるんじゃ
He's under enough pressure
being put in ahead of his seniors.
あそか
Oh, yeah!
ヘイ山口
ん
Hey, Yamaguchi!
(一同)一本ナイサ
Serve up a nice one!
Aoba Jousai                    Karasuno
あちゃガチガチだな
しょうがねぇよ
Oh man. He's awkward as hell.
Of course he is.
Serving is the only time you're truly alone in a sport that involves passing the ball back and forth.
仲間に繋ぐことが全てのバレで
サブは唯一独りの瞬間
全員が自分を見る
プレシャもひとしおだ
Everyone's watching you.
The pressure is intense.
≪怖いでも
This is scary, but...
(嶋田)それでも
サブポジシｮンに立た瞬間は
The moment you stand in the position to serve,
you're the star of the match, no matter who you are!
誰だろうとその試合の主役だ
(山口)≪自分も戦えるて
Prove to them that you can play too!
証明しろ
(２人)≪ジャンプフロタ
A jump float serve?!
(田中･東峰･澤村)≪入れ
Go over!
ピ
(青城応援団)わあ
Rule the Court
Aoba Jousai                   Karasuno
いいぞいいぞ青城
押せ押せ青城
Work it, work it, Seijou! Work it, work it, Seijou!
ふぅ
よしラキ
One more point!
Okay, we got lucky.
(山口)すすみません
(東峰)ドンマイ
I-I'm sorry.
Shake it off!
(田中)き気にすんな
ドンマイ
D-Don't sweat it.
Don't worry about it.
(山口)すみません
(繋心)いや
I'm sorry.
Nah.
(武田)ドンマイですよ山口君
(繋心)気にすんな切り替えろ
Just shake it off, Yamaguchi.
Don't think twice about it. Leave it behind you.
Yamaguchi!
(澤村)山口
あすすみません
I-I'm sorry.
次決めろよ
Make the next one count.
(山口)≪次
The next one?
Yes, sir!
≪烏野空気が変わた
Has Karasuno's mood changed?
主将てすげぇな
Captains are incredible.
I still can't measure up to them.
まだ全然かなわねぇわ
いや今日いちばんの緊張から
解放された気分です
Wow. It's like I've been relieved of the worst stress of the day.
俺もだよ
Same here.
What? They quickly brought him in and
then threw him out again after he failed.
(ユウコ)ええ
ピンチに突然出されて
失敗したら
引込められちゃうんだ
なんかかわいそう
I feel sorry for him.
(嶋田)ピンチサバは
そういう仕事なんだ
That's what pinch servers do.
その一本に試合の流れと
自分のプライド全部乗けてる
The momentum and their pride all rides on that one ball.
そんで忠は失敗した
And Tadashi failed.
One point! One point!
でも今ここで
悔しさと自分の無力さを知る
But this opportunity to learn frustration and his own powerlessness now will definitely make him better!
チャンスがあることが
絶対にあいつを強くする
(田中)だりゃ
ピ
All right!
(ユウコ)
なんか黒い方元気になた
Has the guy with a tan perked up?
(嶋田)確かに
たつぁんの言うとおりかもな
Yeah, you might be right, Tattsuan.
流れは
どからどう変わるか分からない
You never know what event might turn the tide.
(澤村)
≪次を次も戦うチャンスを
Another match!
Earn the chance to play...
≪つかめ
another match!
Daichi, nice receive!
よし切らすな切らすな
Okay, don't lose it now!
≪すぐそこに
見えているようで
It's like the back of Seijou's shirt is within reach,
yet it never gets any closer.
青城の背中ははるか遠く
ブレイクで点をつかめなければ
烏野は負けを待つだけ≫
Unless they score when Seijou is serving, Karasuno is just waiting to lose.
くカバカバ
Cover it!
(繋心)≪疲れで
徐々に打点が下がてきたか
Is exhaustion gradually lowering their accuracy?
(及川)国見ちゃん
あ
Kunimi!
Nice cover!
This is some high-level stuff.
レベル高ぇ
これで３回戦かよ
It's coming back! We have a chance!
Is this really a third-round match?
ピ
アウトか
It's out.
(田中)すんません
I'm sorry!
Aoba Jousai               Karasuno
よし
Okay!
頼むブレイクブレイク
Please score!
ピ
(２人)く
It's out!
アウト
(澤村)ナイスジャジ
Nice eye!
Aoba Jousai               Karasuno
Okay, good!
よしよし
連続でもう一点来い
Ryuu, last hit!
Make it back-to-back points!
Yeah!
Get every ball in front of me!
≪目の前のボル全部
≪足自分の足で
He used his foot!
Right on!
(菅原)よしゃ
(月島)痛そう
That looks painful.
うわぁ
ナイス日向
Nice, Hinata!
(嶋田)ブレイク
(滝ノ上)もう一点
We scored! Just one point behind now!
ピ
影山ナイサ
Aoba Jousai               Karasuno
Kageyama, give us a good serve!
≪もう一点≫
One more point!
(澤村)う
(田中)大地さん
Daichi!
≪負けてたまるか
There's no way in hell I'll lose!
(澤村)≪負けて
There's no way...
≪ああ
Hey...
しゃ
(澤村)≪こいつらも同じだ≫
Yes!
They're the same!
ピ
青城これで
Seijou now has...
Aoba Jousai                    Karasuno
マチポイント
match point!
(青城応援団)
あと１点あと１点
Point, point!
One point to go! One point to go!
あと１点
あと１点あと１点
Don't be intimidated, men!
(西谷)野郎どもビビるな
前のめりで行くぜ
Let's throw ourselves into it!
(一同)はは
ピ
うお
(木下)しゃあ
(縁下)旭さんナイスキ
Yes!
Asahi, nice spike!
One point to go!
(成田)あと１点
(澤村)田中ナイサ
Tanaka, give us a good one!
One point!
一本
(東峰)ナイサ
You can do it!
≪このサブをミスれば
即試合終了≫
If I mess up this serve, it's match over.
≪きれいに拾われてまともに
攻撃決められても終わり≫
If they receive this ball and make their attack count, it's over!
≪速攻来る絶対落とすな
They'll use a fast attack!
Don't let it hit the floor!
At the very least,
せめて
≪触れ
touch it!
あ
(滝ノ上)やべぇネト越える
Shit!
It's going over the net!
ダイレクトでたたかれる
They'll just send it right back over!
≪ワンハンドトス
A one-handed set?
(一同)よしゃ
All right!
Next Episode Preview
Hey, you guys really are throwing yourselves into it!
(西谷)お前らいい感じに
前のめてんじゃねぇか
Thank you, sir!
The score's 24-24. It's deuce.
(日向･影山)あざす
２４対２４デュスだ
Whoever gets ahead by two points first wins.
Obviously, that will be us!
先に２点先取した方が勝つ
(澤村)もちろん勝つのは俺たちだ
All right!
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
(日向･影山･西谷)おしゃ
"'Lonely King' No More."
Episode Twenty-four:
"Lonely King" No More